Research sometimes proves, with data, what we more or less already know (e.g. exercise is good for you, and polluted air isn’t).
研究有时会用数据证明我们多少已经知道的事情（例如，锻炼对身体有益，而污染的空气则对身体无益）。
Still, sometimes our assumptions are incorrect, and scientific findings surprise researchers, along with the rest of us.
不过，有时我们的假设并不正确，科学发现会让研究人员以及我们其他人都感到意外。
A recent example is the phenomenon of disappearing lakes in parts of the frozen treeless Arctic region.
最近的一个例子是，在冰冻、无树的北极地区，部分区域出现了湖泊消失的现象。
You might think these lakes would be expanding, not disappearing.
你可能会以为这些湖泊会不断扩大，而不是消失。
As climate change warms the region — melting surface snow and ice as well as the permafrost — there should be more surface water, forming larger lakes and even new ones.
随着气候变化使该地区变暖——融化地表的冰雪以及永冻层——地表水应该会增多，形成更大的湖泊，甚至形成新的湖泊。
Recently, however, scientists have observed not just shrinking lakes but lakes that have completely gone away.
然而，最近科学家们观察到的不仅有正在缩小的湖泊，还有已经完全消失的湖泊。
Many scientists shared the commonsense expectation that as permafrost melted, lakes would at first expand with meltwater flowing into them.
许多科学家都持有一种常识性的预期：随着永冻层融化，湖泊起初会因融水流入而扩大。
Researchers also predicted that eventually progressive warming during the 21st and 22nd centuries would dry out the Arctic, and lakes would begin to shrink.
研究人员还预测，21世纪和22世纪逐渐加剧的变暖最终会使北极变得干燥，湖泊也会开始缩小。
But now it looks as if Arctic lakes are disappearing a century sooner than predicted.
但现在看来，北极湖泊消失的时间比预测的早了一个世纪。
A case in point is that some large, age-old lakes shrank dramatically in what appears to have been a matter of months.
一个典型的例子是，一些古老的大型湖泊在似乎只有短短几个月的时间里急剧缩小。
Scientists have labeled this phenomenon “disastrous lake loss”.
科学家们将这一现象称为“灾难性湖泊消失”。
What caused this?
是什么导致了这种情况？
The frozen solid ground actually contains bits of rock, mineral and organic matter, leaving spaces in between.
冻得坚硬的地面实际上含有岩石、矿物和有机物的碎块，碎块之间留有空隙。
Because these spaces are filled with solid ice, liquid water cannot readily get inside; when the permafrost melts, however, more water can get through.
由于这些空隙里填满了固态冰，液态水不易渗入；然而，永冻层融化时，更多的水就能渗透进去。
In one case, soon after the permafrost beneath them melted, around 192 lakes in northwestern Alaska disappeared from sight.
有一个例子是，阿拉斯加西北部约192个湖泊在湖底的永冻层融化后不久就消失不见了。
Why did scientists miss this?
科学家们为什么没能预见到这一点？
One probable reason is that most climate models assume that the melting of permafrost is driven only by warming air.
一个可能的原因是，大多数气候模型都假定，永冻层融化仅仅是空气变暖造成的。
New evidence suggests, however, that rainfall — particularly increasing autumn rain — is now contributing significantly to permafrost loss.
然而，新的证据表明，降雨——尤其是日益增多的秋雨——目前正在大大加剧永冻层的消失。
The rainfall carries heat into the ground.
雨水将热量带入地下。
Yet none of the existing models includes such processes.
然而，现有的模型都没有把这样的过程考虑在内。
That is a good example of why — no matter how complex our models are or may one day be — we need direct observation of the natural world.
这很好地说明了为什么无论我们的模型现在有多复杂，或者将来有一天可能变得多复杂，我们都需要对自然界进行直接观测。